Ronald Lewis

BOILER OPERATOR - INOLEX CHEMICAL COMPANY

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Ronald-Lewis/bc962872e5d2f8e3

Highly dedicated, motivated and energetic facilities professional with 5 years of experience, with a commitment to excellence and an outstanding track record of success in overseeing in all aspects of HVAC for a large retail chain store. With outstanding interpersonal communication skills, with the ability to coordinate work outcomes with directors, architects, engineers, facility managers, zoning officials, state and local building inspectors, union representatives, as well as contractors and subcontractors. Highly analytical, budget-conscious individual, who is able to meet deadlines and establish or maintain a high level building maintenance program. A wide-ranging knowledge of and hands on experience with building systems, including HVAC equipment, kitchen equipment, fire suppression systems, electrical distribution systems, elevators, conveyor systems, plumbing systems and refrigeration systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BOILER OPERATOR

INOLEX CHEMICAL COMPANY - 2013 to Present

Operate and Maintain High and Low Pressure Water tube boilers, Provide steam for the manufacture of specialty chemicals, and throughout the complex, Water treatment, and Regenerate polishers and softners, Repair and service oil guns, Heat Exchangers, Blow down boiler, change valves. Work hands on with building system including HVAC systems, AHU'S, cooling towers, York and Tran chillers 2(500 TON) 2(400 TON) Compressors, Fans, Pack Pumps and preventative Maintenance on various other building equipment. Provides detailed communication both written and verbal to supervisor and co workers.

Stationary Engineer

Kirk Bride Center - 2012 to 2013

Work hands on with building systems including HVAC system, Air Handlers, York Chillers, Roof top Units, Exhaust Fans, Fire Tube Boilers Steams Distribution systems, Heat Exchangers, repair and service oil guns, Water Treatment, Preventative Maintenance pumps and various other building equipment.

Building Engineer

School District of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA - 2008 to 2012

Responsible for the operation, maintaining, repair and diagnose of HVAC systems. Responsibilities include but not limited to:

- Worked hands on with building systems including HVAC systems, Water, Fire and Atmospheric Boilers and Steam Distribution system, Heat Exchangers, repair/service oil guns, pm pumps and Air Handles.
- Absorption, Centrifugal and Reciprocating Chillers, Roof Top Packaged Air Conditioners, Exhaust Fans and all relating auxiliary equipment.
- Fire Suppression, Electrical, Plumbing and Water Treatment systems.
- Inspecting maintenance equipment and general repair work of trades mechanics and service technicians to assure quality service and safety for the facility.
- Record all labor, material and equipment cost.
- Plan, develop and manage projects with labor force or outside contractors from concept thru design, documentation and occupancy by clients.

Service Attendant

Temple University Health System - Philadelphia, PA - 2000 to 2009

Responsibilities include but not limited to:

- Cleaning patient rooms and nursing stations
- Operate various floor cleaning machinery
- Clean and strip floors
- Boxed infectious waste
- Run autoclave

Floor Attendant

University of Pennsylvania Hospital - Philadelphia, PA - 1995 to 2000

Responsibilities include but not limited to:

- Cleaning patient rooms and nursing stations
- Operate various floor cleaning machinery
- Clean and strip floors
- · Boxed infectious waste
- Run autoclave

EDUCATION

Diploma in Pennco tech

Peenco Tech Hvac - Bristol, PA 2014 to 2015

Master's

Ferris State University - Big Rapids, MI

Certificate

Philadelphia Academic School

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Facilities Management Financial Management Risk Management
- Project Management Contract Negotiations Estimating & Budgeting Projects
- Detailed Scheduling Contractor Selection DOH Standards & Compliance
- Bid Package Design Schematic Design Review Staff Training & Development
- Energy Management HVAC Technical Expertise Prepare & Prioritizes Work Request